conceptdraw.com 2019-11-18

# Privacy | ConceptDraw

## CS Odessa Personal Privacy Policy

Last updated: October 8, 2019

This Privacy Policy outlines how we collect, store and use data collected from our website [www.conceptdraw.com](https://www.conceptdraw.com/). This policy demonstrates CS Odessa commitment to your privacy and the protection of your personal information. Information obtained from website visitors and customers of our products and services will only be used for the purposes outlined in this policy. Except as specified in this Privacy Policy, at no time will we sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personal information or survey data to a non-agent third party.

Use of our website or products constitutes your agreement with this Privacy Policy, so please read it carefully. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please discontinue use of our website and products immediately. This Privacy Policy may also be updated from time to time, as noted in CS Odessa news and customer announcements. Continued use of our website and products following the announcement of these updates constitutes your agreement with the changes.

## How CS Odessa Collects Personal Information

CS Odessa may collect information about your identity and personal preferences as they relate to our products. Personal information we may collect includes your name, email address, phone number and IP address. If we require additional specific personal information from you, we will inform you at the time of collection about the information we need to collect, the purposes for which it is being collected and how the information will be used, so that you can make an informed decision about whether to provide it. If you choose not to provide requested information, CS Odessa may not be able to provide certain products or services.

There are a number of different ways that CS Odessa receives and collects personal information from you. At no time will we sell or otherwise transfer any of your data to any non-agent third party.

### Registration on www.conceptdraw.com

When you fill out a form on our website, we store the information you provide to us, such as your name, email address, phone number, and contact message. Following the collection of your data using a website form, we may also use marketing or analytics tools to subsequently track certain purchasing and browsing activities, such as website pages visited, time spent on pages, and marketing emails opened or clicked.

Data collected from our website forms and our marketing tools may be used to periodically send marketing notices, product updates, or company news notices to that email address. You may opt-out of receiving these emails at any time by following the Unsubscribe link located in the footer of these emails or by [contacting us](https://helpdesk.conceptdraw.com/ticket.php). We will process your request as soon as possible. We may also use this data in aggregate to improve our overall website performance and product/service offerings.

### Installation and Use of ConceptDraw Products

When you install and use ConceptDraw products, we may use information about your browser type, operating system, hardware, IP address and the functions of the ConceptDraw products and services that you use so that we can facilitate, evaluate and verify your use of our products and services.

### Contacting you

When you email or write to us, you may provide us with your name, contact details, and other personal information in your message.

### Customer Support

You may provide us with personal information when you send us tickets, make a phone call, or email us to request technical assistance with our products or information that you would like to receive about them.

### Email/Direct Mail Campaigns That You Approved

From time to time we may contact you directly by email informing you about upgrades, news, promotions or special offers that we suppose will be interesting to you. When responding to one of these campaigns, you may provide us with personal information. If you want to stop receiving promotional and information materials from us, you can follow the Unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

### Surveys

From time to time we may conduct surveys in respect of our products and services. Participation in our surveys is optional. However, if you respond to one of our surveys, you may provide us with personal information about you. Unless you otherwise consent, we will only use this information to determine the types of offers, products or services that may be of interest to you and to operate and improve our product and services offerings.

## How CS Odessa Uses Personal Information

CS Odessa may use your personal information for the following purposes:

### Product Registration

Information you provide upon registration will be used to keep a record of your product license and will assist CS Odessa in providing support to you when you contact customer support. CS Odessa will also use this information to inform you of any upgrades, new products, promotions or other information that may be of interest to you.

### Product Installation and Use

Information gathered during installation may be used by CS Odessa to authenticate and periodically verify your licensing rights in the product for anti-piracy purposes identify if ConceptDraw product updates are available for your computer prior to sending you a notice to install the new product update; and receive in-product messages from CS Odessa that you have requested to receive.

### Product Purchases

Information needed to properly fill your order will be gathered and stored when you order products on our web site. To process your order, we use the processing service of Digital River, Inc. You can look through the Digital River’s Privacy Statement [here.](https://www.mycommerce.com/privacy-policy)

We also reserve the right to share this data within our group of partners and local resellers. Otherwise, we do not share this information with anyone.

Unless you expressly notify us to the contrary, we will maintain your personal data for future ordering and individual marketing purposes, after the specified services or products have been provided.

Beyond this, our authorization to use and share this data will be restricted to the respective individual consent you grant us.

### News

We may use your personal information to send you newsletters that provide you with articles and information that we believe may be of interest to you.

### Information About ConceptDraw Products

It is important for us to receive feedback from our customers about our products and any features they would like to see in future products. As such, we may use your personal information to contact you about our products and to inform you of upgrades, promotions and new products that may be of interest to you.

### Internal Analysis

We may use the information you provide us with for our own internal statistical and analytical purposes, to evaluate and enhance users’ experience of the Site by identifying customer preferences and purchasing trends that we may use for marketing purposes and in respect of operations and development.

### Updating information

We may contact you to ensure that the information we have in our records is still correct, to add additional information or to communicate with you about an outstanding transaction.

### Special Collaborative Programs

We may collaborate with another company to provide you with a unique product or service. The use of your information by CS Odessa and its collaborators is limited to the specific Collaborative Program that you have joined or elected to use. By using a Collaborative Program, you have given CS Odessa and the collaborating company permission to collect information and provide you with updates, promotions and new Collaborative Program product or service information relating only to the Collaborative Program. To the extent personal information is collected by a third-party collaborator, we will use reasonable commercial efforts to advise you of this fact, and all information collected by such collaborator will be governed by the collaborator’s privacy policy.

## Information Collected Automatically 

Whenever you enter our website or access any on-line information through a ConceptDraw product, our web server may automatically collect and aggregate information in respect of your visit. Automatic Information may include URLs or domains of referring websites, browser type, operating system, the pages that you access and the date and time of your visit. Information collected automatically is used for statistical and marketing purposes. CS Odessa is eligible to share this Information with its partners in order to improve the content, banners and promotions that you and other users will see on our websites and in our products.

## Online Services

You retain full rights of your data uploaded to the online services. We store your data and only provide access by registration information of you and other registered users you chose to collaborate with. We will not sell, share, or rent your data to others in ways different from those disclosed in this Policy.

We use outside vendors and hosting companies to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology required to run our services. We retain full rights of ownership on our software, designs, code, databases, and any other internally developed application to provide our online services.

In addition, certain of our products or services may allow you to store, and share, or otherwise organize or manage files. We may record and store information regarding the size and name of all User Files that you make available via ConceptDraw product and services. Because the names of the User Files you submit are not treated as personal information, we recommend that you do not include any non-public personal information to describe User Files that you make available via these products and services.

## Disclosing Information to Third Parties

We may use the services of third party companies to physically collect, store or remove your information on our behalf. Any such companies will have to comply with the terms of this policy.

Except as specifically described in the present document, CS Odessa will not share any personal information with third parties without obtaining your consent.

Although we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or other legal process or to protect CS Odessa’s, our users’ or third parties’ rights, property or safety.

## Security

We maintain reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information. While no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure from intrusion, we have used and will continue to use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the protection of your personal information.

We use reasonable precautions to protect your personal information and to store it securely. Sensitive information transmitted to us online is encrypted and is transmitted to us securely. In addition, access to all of our customers’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted. Only authorized employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, a billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Finally, the servers on which we store personally identifiable information are maintained in a secure environment.

## Encryption

Personal Information is encrypted using the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) Protocol for browsers that supports 128-bit encryption.

## Cookies

A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser of your computer’s hard disk so that the website can remember who you are and other details. Cookies may be set by a website or originate with third parties, such as advertisers. A cookie itself is not designed or intended to read any information from a user’s computer (other than the contents of the cookie). A cookie is simply an identifier used by the website that originally placed it on your hard drive. The actual contents of the cookie information can be retrieved by the same server to identify the computer and subsequently to customize, track, or regulate the use of a site based on information stored on the host server.

We may make use of cookies on our website. We use cookies to allow us to automate the access and the data entry functions of our website and to correlate online ordering information for purchases you may make while at the website (if any), tailor our website to your preferences or interests, or customize promotions or marketing. In addition, cookies allow us to track use of our website to determine those areas which are useful or popular and those that are not thereby enabling us to improve and update our website effectively.

Most web browsers can either alert you to the use of cookies or refuse to accept cookies entirely. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of the website if cookies are disabled. We do not use flash cookies.

For more information on how to disable cookies, you should consult the documentation or instructions that accompanied your web browser or by visiting the [Federal Trade Commission ](https://www.ftc.gov/ftc/cookies.shtm) website.

## GDPR

We are aware of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). The GDPR covers the collection, storage and processing of personal data from anyone living in the EU. CS Odessa ensures, that we collect and/or use your personal data in accordance with the GDPR, which is confirmed by the content of the current document.

## Your California Privacy rights

Beginning on January 1, 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits those customers that are California residents to request that CS Odessa not share your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing use. To make such a request, submit it [here](https://helpdesk.conceptdraw.com/ticket.php).

## Links

Our websites may contain links to other sites. CS Odessa is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each website to which we may link that may collect personally identifiable information.

## Notice to Parents

Parents or guardians: we want to help you guard your children’s privacy. We encourage you to talk to your children about safe and responsible use of their Personal Information while using the Internet.

CS Odessa websites are general audience sites which are neither designed nor intended to collect any personally identifiable information from children who are under the age of 13.

## Right to View, Correct and Remove Information

We take reasonable steps to ensure that the information that we receive from you is accurate and kept up to date. You have the right to access your personal information, to verify its accuracy, and to correct inaccurate information. You can change your preferences at any time by signing into your account through our website with your credentials (email address and password) or by [contacting us](https://helpdesk.conceptdraw.com/ticket.php).

You have "Right to be forgotten" – the right to have all of your personal data permanently deleted from our systems and records. You may send an appropriate request at the email address, phone number, postal address, or by other means provided at [Contact Us](https://www.conceptdraw.com/products/contact-us) page.

## Storage of Information

We will not retain your information for longer than is necessary for us to use it for the purposes for which it has been collected, unless otherwise required by law or because of pending litigation. When information is no longer required, we will ensure that all such data is removed from our database. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## Store Return Policy

Any fees paid by you for ConceptDraw Products or Solutions are non-refundable. You will be responsible for withholding, filing, reporting, and paying all taxes, duties and other governmental assessments associated with your activity in connection with your purchase (except for taxes on our net income).

## Changes to Privacy Policy

We are always looking for ways to improve our business and our practices. Consequently, our policies will continue to evolve. As such, CS Odessa reserves the right to alter this privacy policy from time to time. Changes to this policy will be posted to [www.conceptdraw.com](https://www.conceptdraw.com/). We encourage you to visit our privacy page from time to time to view our most current privacy policy. If we make material changes to this privacy policy that expand our rights to use your personal information, we will notify you and seek your consent through email or a prominent posting on our website.

## Contact Information

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at [Contact Us](https://www.conceptdraw.com/products/contact-us) page.
